Guide to the Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) General Photograph Collection, 1895-present AIS.Photos
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) General Photograph Collection
1895-present
ULS Archives & Special Collections
AIS.Photos
2 Linear Feet
Photographs from the Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) vertical file and smaller collections gathered under one designation.
Scope and Content Notes
Photographs cover a wide range of topics relating to the history of Pittsburgh including neighborhoods, infrastructure, and landscape. Collection containing loose images which have no formal collection assignment and gathered together under one heading for the purposes of online presentation. Images are contained within the AIS vertical photo file.
Existence and Location of Copies
Digital reproductions of selected images from the collection are online.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Arrangement
Photographs are arranged topically in folders.
Previous Citation
Archives of Industrial Society (AIS) General Photograph Collection, 1895-present, AIS.Photos, Archives Service Center, University of Pittsburgh
Accruals
This collection will continue to receive new photographic images since it is a general collection of AIS photographs.
Photographs; Railroads -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Business and Industry; Pittsburgh (Pa.); Business enterprises -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Church buildings -- Pennsylvania -- Allegheny County; Church architecture -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Architecture, Domestic -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Dwellings -- Photographs; Railroad companies -- Pennsylvania -- Pittsburgh; Transportation; Ethnic groups; Social groups; University of Pittsburgh; Pennsylvania Railroad; Allegheny Valley Railroad Company
- Airplanes, 3 photographs (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 1)
- Allegheny Valley Railroad, ca. 1900-1910 (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 2-3)
  Scope and Content Notes
  Photographic prints and negatives documenting Allegheny Valley Railroad equipment, stations, and employees.
- Arnold, Mary Collection (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 4)
- Baseball (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 5)
- Block House (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 6)
- Bloomfield Bridge (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 7)
- The Bluff, Pittsburgh (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 8)
- Boats (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 9)
- Borkowski, Joseph (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 10)
  Joseph A. Borkowski, a University of Pittsburgh alumni, was Chairman of the Polish Historical Commission during 1960. Photographis in this folder include Borkowski with members of the commission as well as other photographs with Mayor Joseph Barr and Congressman Wililam Moorhead, snapshots taken between 1950 and 1959, and the unveiling of the William B. Foster Memoria (May 15, 1955).
- Bridges (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 11)
- Broom Makers (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 12)
- Buhl Planetarium (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 13)
- Caliguiri, Richard (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 14)
- Carnegie Family (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 15)
- Carpatho-Russians in Western Pa. (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 16-17)
- CCC, 1941 (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 18)
- Central Council of Polish Organizations (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 19)
- Churches--Church of Ascension (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 20)
- Churches--First United Presbyterian Church (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 21)
- Churches--St. Paul's Cathedral (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 22)
- Churches--St. Peter's Episcopal Church (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 23)
- Churches--Third Presbyterian (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 24)
- Cigar Making (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 25)
- City County Building (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 26)
- Civic Arena (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 27)
- Continental Can Company (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 28)
- Court House, October 8, 1934 (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 29)
  Folder contains one printed card documenting the history of courthouses in Pittsburgh and one photograph published by the Pittsburgh Sun-Telegraph with the caption, "Beauty By Night: Courthouse In Its Glory The new nocturnal glory for the country courthosue, nightly showered with light since its thorough cleaning."
- Croatians in Western Pa (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 30)
- Duquesne Light--Construction Crew (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 31)
- Editorial Staff (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 32)
- Ethnic Groups-- Events (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 33-34)
- Faull Drug Store, 1895 (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 35)
- Fisher Body Division of General Motors (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 36)
- Flood of 1936 (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 37)
- Foerester, Tom (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 38)
- Forbes Field, 2 folders (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 39)
- Ford, William H. (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 40)
- Ford City, Pa (Armstrong County), 1935 (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 41)
  Pittsburgh Plate Glass Stirke of 1935
- Fort Duquesne (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 42)
- Frick Fine Arts (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 43)
- Funerals--Mary Cornett (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 44-45)
- Goldberg Fruit Market (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 46)
- Glass Industry (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 47)
- Grant Building (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 48)
- Grayson, John (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 49)
- Greensburg (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 50)
- Gulf Oil Corporation (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 51)
- Bubbe Hannah, ca. 1890-1910 (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 52)
- Harris, Charles "Teenie", 1 folder (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 53)
  Articles, Advertisements, and Photographic Images of Charles "Teenie" Harris.
- Hine, Lewis (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 54)
  Copy negatives of Hine's photographs from the Pittsburgh survey.
- Holy Family Church (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 55)
- Holy Family School (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 56)
- Houses--J.M. Taylor House (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 57)
  Interior and exterior views of the J. M. Taylor house located on Craft Avenue in Pittsburgh's Oakland neighborhood as well as plans showing surrounding streets.
- Houses--Miscellaneous (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 58)
- Housing--Braddock, Pa. (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 59)
- Housing--Homestead (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 60)
- Housing--Pittsburgh (Interior Views), 1939 (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 61)
- Housing--Pittsburgh (External Views), 1939 (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 62)
- Housing--Pittsburgh, ca. 1950-1960 (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 63)
- Hungarians in Western Pa. (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 64)
- Immaculate Heart of Mary Church (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 65)
- Inclines (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 66)
- Individuals--Unidentified, 2 folders (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 67-68)
- Irish in Western Pa. (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 69)
- Italians in Western Pa., 3 folders (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 70-72)
  Photographs of the Sons of Italy Banquet, St. Anthony of Padua Church, and negatives.
- Jewish Americans (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 73)
- Johnstown Flood, 1889 (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 74)
- Johnstown Group Photo (Unidentified) (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 75)
- Jones & Laughlin Steel Corp. (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 76)
- Kings Glass House (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 77)
- Lawrence, David L. (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 78)
- Logan Family (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 79)
- Macedonians in Western Pa. (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 80)
- Manchester House (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 81)
- Mary, Queen of Poland (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 82)
- Mellon Institute (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 83)
- Mexicans in Western Pa., 2 folders (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 84-85)
  Unidentified family photographs and negatives.
- Moore, Charles Core, M.D. (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 86)
- Munhall Neighborhood House (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 87)
- Oakland, Pittsburgh (File-cabinet 17, Drawer 1, Folder 88)
- Oakland, Forbes Field, August 12, 1968; 3 photographs (Map-case 7-6, Folder 179)
  Scope and Content
  Three 16x20 color aerial photographic prints of Oakland taken by Norman W. Schumm August 12, 1968. Identified as 686018-276-B, 686068-274-B, and 686027-271. Used in Leonard G Martin's book, "Forbes Field-Build-It-Yourself." Accession AIS.2015.15
- Oakland, Pittsburgh-Bates St. (Map-case 7-6, Folder 89)
- Oakmont Country Club (Map-case 7-6, Folder 90)
- Office Interior (Date and Location Unknown) (Map-case 7-6, Folder 91)
- Old Economy, Beaver County, Pa. (Map-case 7-6, Folder 92)
- Peacock Coal Company (Map-case 7-6, Folder 93)
- Pennsylvania Railroad (Map-case 7-6, Folder 94)
- Phillips, Robert B.-- Residence (Map-case 7-6, Folder 95)
- Pittsburgh--Bureau of Water (Map-case 7-6, Folder 96)
- Pittsburgh--Chamber of Commerce (Map-case 7-6, Folder 97)
- Pittsburgh--Department of City Controller Picnic (Map-case 7-6, Folder 98)
- Pittsburgh--Downtown (Map-case 7-6, Folder 99)
- Pittsburgh--Flood, 1874 (Map-case 7-6, Folder 100)
- Pittsburgh--Fort Wayne and Chicago Railroad Station (Map-case 7-6, Folder 101)
- Pittsburgh--the Great Tunnel (Map-case 7-6, Folder 102)
- Pittsburgh--Industrial Scenes (Map-case 7-6, Folder 103-105)
- Pittsburgh & Lake Erie Railroad (Map-case 7-6, Folder 106)
  Wreck at College Station.
- Pittsburgh Pirates (Map-case 7-6, Folder 107)
- The Point (Map-case 7-6, Folder 108)
- Pittsburgh Scenes (Map-case 7-6, Folder 109)
- Pittsburgh Scenes-Brighton Recreation Parlor (Map-case 7-6, Folder 110)
- Pittsburgh Scenes-Children (Map-case 7-6, Folder 111)
- Pittsburgh Scenes-Lawrenceville-Doughboy Square (Map-case 7-6, Folder 112)
- Pittsburgh Steelers (Map-case 7-6, Folder 113)
- Pittsburgh Symphony Orchestra Featuring Andre Previn (Map-case 7-6, Folder 114)
- Playgrounds- Hill District (Map-case 7-6, Folder 115)
- Polish Americans (Map-case 7-6, Folder 116-117)
- Polish Consulate of the U.S. (Map-case 7-6, Folder 118)
- Polish Day (Map-case 7-6, Folder 119)
- Polish Falcons of America (Map-case 7-6, Folder 120- 122)
- Polish National Alliance (Map-case 7-6, Folder 123-124)
- Polish Roman-Catholic Union (Map-case 7-6, Folder 125)
- Polish in Western Pa. (Map-case 7-6, Folder 126)
- Pony Express (Map-case 7-6, Folder 127)
- Pope John Paul II (Wojtyla, Karol Cardinal) (Map-case 7-6, Folder 128)
- Portraits--Late 18th to Early 19th c.--Women (Map-case 7-6, Folder 129)
- Portraits--Unidentified (Map-case 7-6, Folder 130)
- Rafting-Susquehenna River (Map-case 7-6, Folder 131)
- Railroad-Steam Car (Map-case 7-6, Folder 132)
- Sample, William (Map-case 7-6, Folder 133)
- School, Pittsburgh Public--Bellfield (Map-case 7-6, Folder 134)
- Schools, Pittsburgh Public--Fifth Avenue High School (Map-case 7-6, Folder 135)
- Schools, Pittsburgh Public--Grant School (Map-case 7-6, Folder 136)
- School, Pittsburgh Public--Holmes, ca. 1884-1901 (Map-case 7-6, Folder 137)
- Schools, Pittsburgh Public--Martin School (Map-case 7-6, Folder 138)
- Schools, Pittsburgh Public--Shakespeare School (Map-case 7-6, Folder 139)
- Slovaks in Western Pa. (Map-case 7-6, Folder 140)
- Slovaks in Western Pa.--Church of SS. Cyril & Methodius (Map-case 7-6, Folder 141)
- Slovaks in Pennsylvania (Map-case 7-6, Folder 142)
  Four post cards from the Jednota Museum in Middleton, PA.
- Smoke Abatement, ca. 1950- 1959 (Map-case 7-6, Folder 143)
- Soho Community House (Map-case 7-6, Folder 144)
- South Park Skating Rink (Map-case 7-6, Folder 145)
- South Side, Pittsburgh--18th Street (Map-case 7-6, Folder 146-147)
  Prints and copy negatives for views of 18th Street.
- South Side, Pittsburgh--Miscellaneous (Map-case 7-6, Folder 148)
  Views of South Side families, businesses, and groups.
- Steel Industry, USS, Pittsburgh, PA; 1956, . (Map-case 7-6, Folder 149)
  Images of steel workers performing various jobs and letter from W. Everette McLaine to Richard S. Dowty Jr.
- Stores--Joseph Horne Co. (Map-case 7-6, Folder 150)
- Stores--Mrs. H. F. Vegeler Millinery (Map-case 7-6, Folder 151)
- Stores--Rom's Wholesale Grocer, ca. 1949 (Map-case 7-6, Folder 152)
- Stores--Sun Drug Company Warehouse, ca. 1930s (Map-case 7-6, Folder 153)
- Stores--Woolworth Co., ca. 1946 (Map-case 7-6, Folder 154)
- Streets--East Street, ca. 1920 (Map-case 7-6, Folder 155)
- Streets--Street Scenes-Dates Unknown (Map-case 7-6, Folder 156)
- Streets--Street Scenes-ca. Early 20th Century, 1900-1920 (Map-case 7-6, Folder 157)
- Symroski, Charles A., 1966 (Map-case 7-6, Folder 158)
- Taft, William Howard, 1908-1909 (Map-case 7-6, Folder 159)
- Thompson, J. V., Advertisement for the First National Bank of Uniontown, PA (Map-case 7-6, Folder 160)
- Ukranians in Western Pa.- "Lemko Wedding", ca. 1936 (Map-case 7-6, Folder 161)
- Ukranians in Pennsylvania (Map-case 7-6, Folder 162)
- U.S. Steel, Homestead Works (Map-case 7-6, Folder 163)
- Veterans of Foreign Wars (Map-case 7-6, Folder 164)
  Photos of Veterans, the Historical Plaque for the founding of a V.F.W., and a letter from Francis Barry to Joseph Borkowski.
- Veteran's Hospital-Oakland (Map-case 7-6, Folder 165)
- Waring Court, ca. 1960 (Map-case 7-6, Folder 166)
  Street scene taken by Miss Chips.
- Waynesburg and Washington Railroad Photo Collection (Map-case 7-6, Folder 167)
  Sixty four photographic prints showing railroad equipment, crossings, stations, and platforms.
- Weddings (Map-case 7-6, Folder 168)
- West Newton, Pa. (Westmoreland County) Church (Map-case 7-6, Folder 169)
- West Penn Hospital (Map-case 7-6, Folder 170)
- Windber, Pa. (Somerset County) (Map-case 7-6, Folder 171-172)
- Wind Gap School (Map-case 7-6, Folder 173)
  Views of the school, students, teachers and the Wind Gap School Entertainment Program.
- Women--Interior Work (Map-case 7-6, Folder 174)
- World War II (Map-case 7-6, Folder 175)
- Wright, John Cardinal, 1960 (Map-case 7-6, Folder 176)
  Cardinal John Wright during his time as Bishop of Pittsburgh.
- Wrought Iron Making (Map-case 7-6, Folder 177)
- Yablonsky, Joseph (Map-case 7-6, Folder 178)